Abdurahmon Usmonov

Strong Junior Mern Stack Engineer

Uzbekistan, Namangan | +99899 399 36 67 | coderusmonov@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdurahmondev

CAREER SUMMARY:

Junior Software Engineer with over 3 month of production experience building scalable and performant mern stack web applications to deliver exceptional user experience and interface in E-commerce and have little experience working in Agile (Scrum & Kanban).

SKILLS:

- JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Nodejs
- Redux, React Testing Library, Express.js
- MongoDB, Git, REST API
- Styled-components

EDUCATION:

01 / 2024 - Present | **University of Business and Science, Namangan, Uzbekistan**Bachelor of information systems and technologies - Software Engineering (extramural)

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Namangan Institute of Engineering and Construction

Junior Software Engineer | 01 July, 2024 – 30 September, 2024

- Collaborated with product management, design, and backend teams on daily basis to gather feature requirements and deliver them on time!
- Helped to increase test coverage from 70% to 100% using the Jest and React Testing Library!
- Set up push notifications and deep linking using Firebase and React Navigation for a banking application!

Oxygenhouse.com

Attractive Houses residential complex website

junior Front-End Engineer | 01 july, 2024 - 15 August, 2024

- Developed a " Dashboard" section using Apollo-boost, React, and Vite with a tight deadline!
- Collaborated on the development of "interactive components" using the React-query library!
- Set up the project automation 'OTA' feature with Microsoft App Center and React for a faster deployment!
- Assisted the team in transitioning from MobX to Redux Toolkit for better state management leveraging features like 'Redux Time Travel' to enhance debugging and application stability!

Nammqi.uz

University offers a comprehensive online platform that provides students and faculty with essential and resources for course management, enrollment, event scheduling, and much more!

Software Engineer | 15 August, 2024 - 20 September, 2024

- For three weeks, contributed to the development of the "University" platform using React, Ant Design and Material-UI!
- A GRID framework developed using React and Ant Design for the front-end team to enhance workflow efficiency!

numa-kids.uz

Next-generation Nutritional Support for Kids. Elevating children's health and wellness. Provide the essentials, nurture their growth!

Software Engineer | 15 August, 2024 - 30 September, 2024

- Developed the client feed screen using React!
- Developed a single-page application using React, providing essential nutritional information and resources for parents to support their children's health!

PERSONAL PROJECTS

E-commerce (Mern Stack Web application)

E-commerce footwear platform

Software Engineer | 30 September, 2024 - 15 October, 2024

- Built an e-commerce website and Web application using React, Redux and node, express!
- E-commerce is a shoe store. add, change, delete products on the dashboard.
 In addition, registered user data and incoming order statistics are followed by Sales statistics, Product statistic!

YouTube-Media

YouTube_Video_Player platform

Software Engineer | 15 October, 2024 - 21 October, 2024

- Built an Web application using React, Rest Api!
- This project is designed as a platform that allows users to interactively view and manage YouTube videos!

gym-exercise

This platform is a modern web application that allows users to learn and track different types of exercise!

Software Engineer | 21 October, 2024 - 27 October, 2024

Built a single page web application using React and Material-UI!

•	The platform helps users plan their workouts, track workouts and improve their fitness. It is provided with an intuitive interface and many functions for users!